# LAURKAN RODRIGUEZ, Bsc. Hons.

Email: laurkanr@gmail.com
GitHub: github.com/lorkaan

## **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

A language-agnostic, full stack software engineer with 5 years of professional experience. Professional specialties include: distributed computing, prototyping, and scalable implementations. A dependable, creative team player with a background in Artificial Intelligence, a curiosity in Cyber Security and a belief in modular software architecture.

#### FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE -

- JavaScript, HTML, Python, C++, C#, Bash
- UI & UX Design, React, Babel, Webpack, CSS
- MVP Prototyping, Automation, Concurrency
- Web App Development, REST, MVC, LAMP
- Linux, Git, Flask, Node, Apache, Databases
- Machine Learning, Neural Networks, AI

## RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

QUILLSOFT LTD 2015 – 2019

**Junior Software Engineer** 2015 – 2017 **Software Engineer** 2017 – 2019

- **Web App Development:** Actualized conceptual features and innovations into functional software products. Implementation was mostly JavaScript within the Chrome browser environment. Development environment included: version control (Git), packaging (Webpack), backwards compatibility (Babel) and automation (Python & Bash scripting)
- **UI & UX Design:** Collaborated in a small team to design simple, accessible and modern user interfaces, mainly utilizing HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Additionally, implemented asynchronous and event based programming to ensure these user interfaces are responsive, dynamic and intuitive.
- **MVP Prototyping:** Created Minimal Viable Product demos integrating of third-party libraries, new technologies or innovative features into current or future software projects. Examples of MVPs include: React Containers for accessible UI elements, a C# implementation of software products, and the integration of a C++ library into WebAssembly for local data processing.
- Additional Responsibilities: Managed a software development intern, teaching them about advanced data structures and guiding them towards good practices. Involved in high-level decisions about software architecture, implementation and functionality based upon user requirements, efficiency and future upgrades.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Honours Bachelor of Science (Computer Science & Cognitive Science)**

2010 - 2015

University of Toronto (Toronto, Canada)

Studies touched on neuroscience, psychology, philosophy and computer science, with the objective of understanding the human brain via modeling it through Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. Skills obtained during this time include Machine Learning techniques, implementing Augmented Data Structures and Algorithm Design.

## **OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS**

These projects function as modular libraries, designed to be incorporated into larger projects. 2019 - 2020

Pexpect Parser
 Data Structures
 Kaan Types
 An abstraction layer for command line automation using the Pexpect API
 My personal toolkit of custom-made, generic data structures in Python
 A JavaScript library enabling more readable function input validation

For more details, please visit my GitHub page.